Guide to the Joseph Brodsky Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, circa 1959-2000; Series II; 33.99; (86 boxes)
  - Notebooks
    Dates of the notebooks in this Subseries are tentative. Many notebooks span several years and Brodsky may have revisited them at later dates.
    - Notebook, blue "Kantseliarskaia kniga", 1960s (Box 36, Folder 752)
      Includes the poems Kulik and Babochka.
    - Notebook, bound in houndstooth patterned board, 1970s (Box 36, Folder 753)
      Includes the poem Piataia godovshchina.
    - Notebook, bound "Kniga ucheta" with drawings by Brodsky on the cover, 1970-1972 (Box 36, Folder 754)
      Includes the poem Debiut and translations of the poetry of Umberto Saba.
    - Notebook bound in red leather, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 755)
      A gift from Frida Vigdorova; includes a partial description of Brodsky's emigration from the Soviet Union and a dedication from Efim Etkind.
    - Notebook, blue with red and white dots, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 756)
      Includes the poems Laguna and Nad vostochnoi rekoi.
    - Loose sheets from a quad-ruled notebook, 1973-1984 (Box 36, Folder 757)
      Includes the poem Litovskii Noktiurn.
    - Notebook, black, 1974-1990 (Box 36, Folder 758)
      Includes the poems Polden' v komnate, Kentavry II, Ekloga vesnaia and Pis'mo v oazis.
      Accompanied by a detailed table of contents written by Lev Losev.
    - Notebook, spiral-bound "University of Michigan", 1977 (Box 36, Folder 759)
    - Notepad, white "Belyi kit na snosiakh?", 1977?
    - Notebook, white "Triomphe", 1980s (Box 36, Folder 760)
      Includes an unidentified poem in English on the cover.
    - Notebook, black "Risma uno", 1980s (Box 36, Folder 761)
      Includes the poem "Vecher. Razvaliny geometrii" and an English translation of the poem Kvintet (Sextet).
    - Notebook, gray "Laboratory notebook", 1980s (Box 37, Folder 762)
      Inclues the poem Ekloga IV-aia and other Russian-language poems.
    - Notepad, unlined, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 763)
      Includes the poems Predstavlenie and "IA byl tol'ko tem."
    - Notebook, blue "University of Michigan", circa 1980 (Box 37, Folder 764)
      Includes the poems Venetsianskie Strofy and "Povernis' ko mne v profil'."
    - Notebook, white with black musical notes, 1980? (Box 37, Folder 765)
      Includes the introduction to A tomb for Boris Davidovich by Danilo Kiš.
    - Notebooks (two), blue "Examination book", circa 1981 (Box 37, Folder 766)
      Includes and English translation of the poem Rimskie Elegii.
    - Notepad, unlined, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 767)
      Includes the poems Otkrytka iz Neboskreba and "Bosoi s nabriakshim..."
    - Notebook, black hard-bound, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 768)
      Includes Rimskie elegii, "IA byl tol'ko tem, chego" and short poems in English.
    - Legal pad, lined, 1981-1983 (Box 37, Folder 769)
      Includes an English translation of the poem Rimskie elegii.
    - Notebook, uncovered quad-ruled pages, 1982-1987 (Box 37, Folder 770)
      Includes the poems Nazidanie and V okrestnostiakh Aleksandrii.
    - Notebook, green hard-bound, 1985-1986 (Box 37, Folder 771)
      Includes the poems "V etoi komnate pakhlo triap'em i syroi vodoi," and "Zamerzshii kisel'nyi bereg. Priachushchii v moloke."
    - Notebook, black, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 772)
      Includes the poem Posleslovie.
    - Notebook, green "Jolly", 1987-1988 (Box 37, Folder 773)
      Includes the poems Rozhdesvenskaia zvezda and Elegiia ("Postoianstvo sut' evoliutsiia...").
    - Notebook, bound in brown leather, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 774)
      Includes notes on boredom.
    - Notebook, black "Quaderno", circa 1989-1990 (Box 38, Folder 775)
      Includes the poems Arkhitektura, Fin de Siècle, and Na stoletie Anny Akhmatovoi.
    - Notebook, blue "Marie papier", 1990s (Box 38, Folder 776)
      Includes an English-language essay on human rights and the poem "Once upon a time there was a cat."
    - Notebook, black, 1990-1992 (Box 38, Folder 777)
      Includes the poems "Vot ia i snova pod etim vestsvetnym nebom," Vertumn, Portret tragedii and the essay "An immodest proposal."
    - Notebook, red "Memo book", circa 1991 (Box 38, Folder 778)
      Includes the essay "An immodest proposal."
    - Notebook, purple, circa 1992 (Box 38, Folder 779)
      Includes the poem Transatlantic.
    - Legal pad, white lined, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 780)
      Includes English translations of the poems Novaia Zhizn', Fin de Siècle and "Konchitsia leto. Nachnetsia sentiabr'. Razreshat otstrel."
    - Notebook, bound in red calfskin, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 781)
      Includes addresses and phone numbers.
    - Legal pad, purple, lined, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 782)
      Includes an English translation of the poem Kappadokiia and unidentified Russian- and English-language poems.
    - Legal pad, pink, lined, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 783)
      Includes an English translation of the poem Kolybel'naia ("Rodila tebe v pustyne").
    - Notebook, red pocket size "Grand Hotel Excelsior", 1993 (Box 38, Folder 784)
      Includes phone numbers and to-do lists.
    - Notebook, black, bound "A. Bottarelli", circa 1994 (Box 39, Folder 785)
      Includes the poems Posle nas razumeetsia ne potop and Iz Al'berta Einshteina.
    - Notebook, black "Quaderno", 1995 (Box 39, Folder 786)
      Includes the poem "Starik, pishu tebe po-novoi."
    - Notebook bound in blue marbled paper, undated (Box 39, Folder 787)
      Includes unidentified poems in Russian and of the essay "In the shadow of Dante."
    - Notepad, "Pocket legal", undated (Box 39, Folder 788)
      Includes two pages of unidentified Russian-language poetry.
    - Notebook, bound in houndstooth patterned board, undated (Box 39, Folder 789)
      A gift from Marty Myers.
      Includes the poem "Gorod znakom budto ty v nem vyros i pokhoronen."
    - Notebook, black "Esselte", undated (Box 39, Folder 790)
      Contains fragments of unidentified English- and Russian-language poetry.
    - Notebook, black with white lines, spiral bound, undated (Box 39, Folder 791)
      Includes the poem "Vspomnim Baltiiskii flot i uchinim ..."
    - Notebook, black and white, undated (Box 39, Folder 792)
      Includes an English translation of the poem Lido.
    - Notebook, blue, undated (Box 39, Folder 793)
    - Notebook, black with red edges, undated (Box 39, Folder 794)
    - Writing tablet, "Square deal", undated (Box 39, Folder 795)
      Includes drafts of letters in Brodsky's hand and in unidentified handwriting.
    - Restricted material (notebooks), circa 1972-1996 (Box 40, Folder 796-802)
      See: MS Vault Film 2524.
      Original notebooks are partially restricted until 2071. Microfilm of unrestricted portions is available.
      Unrestricted pages include drafts of writings.
  - Poetry
    Poetry consists of holograph and typescript drafts, proofs, and printed versions of poems and poetry collections. Some material is photocopies. Though several samizdat collections date to before Brodsky's emigration from the Soviet Union and some printed collections date to after his death, most material dates from 1972-1996.
    Brodsky's poetry spans a wide range of genres, including children's poems, occasionals, short and long poems (stikhotvoreniia and poemy) and cycles. Many of the English-language translations of Brodsky's poetry are autotranslations and he also collaborated with others to produce authorized English translations. While most of his poetry was written in Russian, some of his later poems were English-language originals.
    Printed Collections are book-length collections of Brodsky's poems, compiled by Brodsky and editors. Samizdat Collections are book-length collections that circulated in the Soviet Union without being formally published. Printed Selections consist of selected poems that were printed in serials or compilations. Individual Poems include drafts, proofs and printed versions of poems outside the context of collections. Many of these poems also appeared in printed collections or selections.
    Poetry is organized under four headings: Printed Collections, Samizdat Collections, Printed Selections, and Individual Poems. Printed Collections are arranged alphabetically by title of work. Samizdat Collections are arranged roughly chronologically. Printed Selections are arranged alphabetically by title of the publication in which the poetry was printed. Individual Poems are arranged alphabetically by title or, for untitled poems, by first line. Unidentified collections, selections and poems are filed at the end of each listing.
    - Printed Collections
      - Chast' Rechi (Ann Arbor, Michigan: Ardis, 1977)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 41, Folder 803-805)
        - Book cover, [1977] (Box 41, Folder 806)
      - Collected Poems in English (New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 2000)
        - Drafts, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 807-811)
        - Drafts, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 812-817)
        - Drafts, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 818-819)
        - Proofs, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 820-823)
        - Proofs, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 824-829)
        - Proofs, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 830-834)
      - Joseph Brodsky: Selected Poems (Baltimore: Penguin, 1973)
        - Draft, circa 1973 (Box 46, Folder 835)
      - Kappadokiia (Saint Petersburg: Peterburgskoe Solo, 1993)
        - Printed version, copy, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 836)
      - Kholmy (Saint Petersburg: LP VTPO Kinotsentr, 1991)
        - Printed version, copy, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 837)
      - Konets Prekrasnoi Epokhi
        - (Ann Arbor, Michigan: Ardis, 1977), book cover (Box 46, Folder 838)
        - (Saint Petersburg: Pushkinskii Fond, 2000), proofs (Box 46, Folder 839-840)
      - Nazidanie (Leningrad: SP "Smart")
        - Printed version, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 841)
          Annotated by Brodsky and signed by friends of Brodsky.
      - Ostanovka v Pustine
        - (Ann Arbor, Michigan: Ardis, 1988), corrigenda, undated (Box 46, Folder 842)
        - (Saint Petersburg: Pushkinskii Fond, 2000)
          - Proofs, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 843-845)
          - Proofs, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 846-848)
      - A Part of Speech (New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1980)
        - List of translators, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 849)
        - Author's note, draft, circa 1979 (Box 47, Folder 850)
        - Printed version, corrected by Brodsky, copy, undated (Box 47, Folder 851)
      - Peizazh s Navodneniem
        - (Dana Point, California: Ardis, 1995)
          - Drafts, 1986-1994, undated (Box 47, Folder 852-859)
          - Drafts, 1986-1994, undated (Box 48, Folder 860-862)
          - Proofs, 1994-1996 (Box 48, Folder 863-868)
        - (Saint Petersburg: Pushkinskii Fond, 2000)
          - Proofs, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 869-870)
          - Proofs, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 871)
      - Quinquagenario Josepho Brodskio
        - Proof, undated (Box 49, Folder 872)
      - Roman Elegies (New York: Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1984)
        - Front matter, draft, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 873)
        - Proof, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 874)
      - Rozhdestvenskie Stikhi (Moscow: Nezavisimaia gazeta, 1996)
        - Book cover and artwork for cover, circa 1996 (Box 49, Folder 875)
      - So Forth (New York: Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1996)
        - Notes by Ann Kjellberg, [1990s] (Box 49, Folder 876)
        - Notes by Aleksandr Sumerkin, [1990s] (Box 49, Folder 877)
        - Notes by Kees Verheul, [1990s] (Box 49, Folder 878)
        - Poems excluded by Brodsky, drafts and printed versions, 1992
        - Drafts, 1993-1995 (Box 49, Folder 879-886)
        - Drafts, 1995-1996, undated (Box 50, Folder 887-891)
        - Proofs, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 892-895)
        - Proofs, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 896-900)
        - Book jacket, 1996
      - To Urania (New York: Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1988)
        - Drafts, 1987-1988, undated (Box 51, Folder 901-905)
          Also available through Access Services: Disk#02; CONTENTS, LONG, OTHERS, POEMS and SHORT.
        - Drafts, 1987-1988, undated (Box 52, Folder 906)
        - Proofs, 1987-1988 (Box 52, Folder 907-909)
      - Uraniia (Ann Arbor, Michigan: Ardis, 1987)
        - Draft, undated (Box 52, Folder 910)
      - V Okrestnostiakh Atlantidy (Saint Petersburg: Pushkinskii Fond, 1995)
        - Table of contents, undated (Box 52, Folder 911)
      - Untitled collection, after 1988 (Box 52, Folder 912-913)
        Possibly a planned publication for Russica Publishers.
      - Unidentified printed collections, photocopies of printed versions, 1993, undated (Box 52, Folder 914-916)
    - Samizdat collections
      Maramzin's four-volume Samizdat collection of Brodsky's work is filed under Collected Works.
      - Poems from 1957-1962, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 917)
        From Masha Vorobiov.
        Pages are numbered 54-107. Includes many poems not found elsewhere in the Papers, particularly those dating from the late 1950s.
      - Iiul'skoe Intermetstso, photocopy of typescript, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 918)
        From Sergei Shults.
      - Stikhotvoreniia, photocopy of a typescript from 1962, undated (Box 53, Folder 919)
      - Pesni Schastlivoi Zimy, copies of typescript, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 920-921)
        Compiled by Vladimir Maramzin.
      - Poems from 1958-1969, typescript and holograph drafts, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 922)
        From Viktor Golyshev.
        Includes translations of Andrew Marvell and Richard Wilbur, the poems Odinochestvo, Piligrimy, Uprazhnenie v konformizme, Osvoenie kosmosa, Kamernaia muzyka, and Iu. Sandul, among many other poems.
        Includes holograph drafts of the poems "Ia probudilsia ves' v potu", "Sem' let spustia."
      - Poems from the 1960s-1972, typescript, undated (Box 53, Folder 923-924)
        Sent from Viktor Golyshev to Ann Kjellberg.
        Includes the poems Bol'shaia elegiia Dzhonu Donnu, "Vse chuzhdo v dome novomu zhil'tsu," "Pod vecher on vidit, zastyvshi v dveriakh," Pesni schastlivoi zimy, "My ne p'em vina na kraiu derevni," "IA vsegda tverdil, chto sud'ba -- igra" and others.
      - Poems from the 1960s and 1970s, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 925)
        Includes Russian translations by Brodsky of the poetry of Richard Wilbur, Stanisław Jerzy Lec, Cyprian Norwid, Umberto Saba, and Vítězlav Nezval, among other poems.
      - Samizdat poems from the 1970s, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 926)
        From Brodsky's briefcase.
      - Brodsky's translations of metaphysical poets, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 927)
      - Brodsky's translations, typescript, undated (Box 53, Folder 928)
        Includes translations of Richard Wilbur, Andrew Marvell, Reed Whittemore, Randall Jarrell and John Donne
      - Children's poems, typescript, undated (Box 53, Folder 929)
        Contains: Ssora, Ianvar', Slon i Marus'ka, Sentiabr', Letniaia muzyka, Pirat, V 6 chasov pod novyi god, Obeshchaniia puteshestvennika, Tri boltuna, Chistoe utro, Iul', and Koshach'i budni.
      - Poems from the late 1960s and 1970s (Box 53, Folder 930)
        From Ardis Publishers.
      - Fragment of a samizdat collection from the 1960s and 1970s, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 931)
    - Printed Selections
      Printed selections are printed versions unless otherwise specified. Many are photocopies.
      - Bananas, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 932)
      - Contemporary Russian Poetry, 1987 (Box 54, Folder 933)
      - Ekho, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 934-935)
      - Et cetera, Bulgarian translations by Georgi Rupchev, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 936)
      - Gavanam, Tamil translations by A. Rajaram, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 937)
      - The Iowa Review, English translations by Daniel Weissbort, corrected by Brodsky, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 938)
      - Iskorka, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 939)
      - Književna Reč, Serbian translations by Srđan Đurđov Rašković, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 940)
      - Književna Reč, Serbian translations by Milovan Danojlić, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 941)
      - Kontinent, 1977-1987, undated (Box 54, Folder 942-943)
      - Leninskie Iskry, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 944-945)
      - Literaturnaia Gruziia, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 946)
      - Mansarda, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 947)
      - Neva, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 948)
      - The new Russian poets, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 949)
      - Nezavisimaia Gazeta, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 950)
      - Novyi Mir, draft and printed version, 1993-1994 (Box 54, Folder 951-952)
        Includes the poem Pesnia v krasnom svitere.
      - Occasional Stiles, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 953)
      - Portfel': Literaturnyi Sbornik (Dana Point, California: Ardis), proof, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 954)
      - La Quinzaine littéraire, French translations by Véronique Schlitz, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 955)
      - [ Republika ?], Serbian translations by Milovan Danojlić, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 956)
      - Russian literature triquarterly, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 957)
      - Selected translations, by W. S. Merwin, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 958)
      - Vestnik, 1973-1977 (Box 54, Folder 959)
      - Vozdushnye puti, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 960)
      - Wilson Quarterly, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 961)
      - Znamia, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 962)
        In addition to selected poems, includes Russian translations of the essays "How to read a book," "In praise of boredom," and "Letter to a President."
      - Zvezda, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 963)
      - Untitled, poetry of Czesław Miłosz, Russian translation by Brodsky, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 964)
      - Unidentified printed selections, 1972-1995, undated (Box 54, Folder 965-974)
        Includes Polish translations by Eugenia Siemaszkiewicz, French translations by an unidentified translator and Armenian translations by Arshavir Mckertich.
    - Individual Poems
      Individual Poems are holograph and typescript drafts, proofs and printed versions outside the context of a printed collection. Some drafts are photocopies. Printed versions include clippings and photocopies from serials such as The New Yorker and The Times Literary Supplement.
      Translators are identified where their names are in evidence.
      Dates in square brackets are informed by Sochineniia Iosifa Brodskogo. Other details such as dates and names of translators have occasionally been verified in Collected Poems in English.
      Arranged alphabetically by title or, for untitled poems, first line. The first line of an untitled poem is indicated by quotation marks (e.g. "A potom nachalsia snegopad"). Untitled poems beginning with the articles "a" and "the" are filed under these words (e.g. "The water gets colder as the ocean heaves" is filed under the, while The tale is filed under tale). Translations of Brodsky's poems are collated with originals under the original-language title. Translations of others' poems by Brodsky are filed according to the English- or Russian-language title of Brodsky's translation.
      - 1 ianvaria 1965 goda, draft and printed version, 1965, 2000, undated (Box 55, Folder 975)
      - 1 sentiabria 1939 goda, English translation by Brodsky, draft
        - Russian language version
          See: Series XI, Papers of Others -- Others -- Ramunas and Elmira Katilius family archive
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft, undated (Box 55, Folder 976)
      - 1972 god
        - Russian language version, drafts, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 977)
        - English interlinear translation by Masha Vorobiov, draft, undated (Box 55, Folder 978)
        - English translation by Bernard Meares, draft, 1978, undated (Box 55, Folder 979)
        - English translation by Alan Myers and Brodsky, drafts and printed versions, 1978-1979 (Box 55, Folder 980-981)
      - 1983, draft, undated (Box 55, Folder 982)
      - 24 dekabria 1971 goda, English translation by Alan Myers, drafts and printed version, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 983-984)
      - 25.XII.1993, drafts (Box 55, Folder 985)
        See also: Series XI, Papers of Others -- Masha Vorobiov Papers -- Correspondence -- Muchnic, Helen
      - "A bright little tear"
        See: Pesenka ("Prolituiu slezu")
      - A. Frolof (Iz shkol'noi antologii), draft, 1969 (Box 55, Folder 986)
        Includes a draft of Didona i Enei.
      - "A potom nachalsia snegopad," draft, undated (Box 55, Folder 987)
      - "A room in an afternoon. That sort of calm"
        See: Polden' v komnate
      - "A Swedish Miss" (occasional to Sara Jangfeldt), draft, 1992 (Box 55, Folder 988-989)
      - Ab ovo, drafts and printed version, 1996 (Box 55, Folder 990)
      - Abroad, drafts, proof and printed version, 1995, undated (Box 55, Folder 991)
        See also: "Sir, you are tough, and I am tough"
      - Achilles. Penthesilea, by Zbigniew Herbert, English translation by Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1993 (Box 55, Folder 992)
      - An admonition
        See: Nazidanie
      - Advice to a traveller
      - Aere perennius, drafts, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 993)
      - "Aeroplan padaet, padaet, padaet, padaet," drafts, undated (Box 55, Folder 994)
      - After Parmenides, draft, undated (Box 55, Folder 995)
      - After Ptolemy
        See: MCMXCV
      - After the last bulletins, by Richard Wilbur, Russian translation by Brodsky
        See: Posle poslednikh isvestii
      - After us, drafts and printed version, 1996, undated (Box 55, Folder 996)
      - Afterword
        See: Posleslovie
      - Akrostikh, draft, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 997)
        Includes a drawing by Brodsky.
      - Allenby road, drafts and proof, [1981] (Box 55, Folder 998)
        See also: Shvedskaia Muzyka
        Proof includes a proof of North Baltic.
      - Almost an elegy
        See: Pochti elegiia
      - "America first was discovered by fish," draft, undated (Box 55, Folder 999)
      - "An autumn evening in the modest square"
        See: "Osennii vecher v skromnom gorodke"
      - Angel
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1990] (Box 55, Folder 1000)
          See also: Nadpis' na knige and Series XI, Papers of Others -- Masha Vorobiov Papers -- Correspondence -- Muchnic, Helen
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proofs and printed version, 1993 (Box 55, Folder 1001)
      - "Angliiskie kamennyi derevni"
        See: V Anglii (I-VII)
      - Anno Domini, drafts, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 1002)
        See also: Series XI, Papers of Others -- Others -- Ramunas and Elmira Katilius family archive
        One draft includes several poems on a single typed page: Zimniaia svad'ba, Shest' let spustia, Orfei i Artemida, Dla shkol'nogo vozrasta, Elegiia (Podruga...). A holograph note identifes the poems Anno Domini and Shest' let spustia as the most "essential."
      - Anthem, drafts and printed version, 1995-1996 (Box 55, Folder 1003-1004)
      - Anti-Shenandoah, drafts and proofs, [1992]-1994 (Box 55, Folder 1005)
      - Aqua vita nuova, draft, [1970] (Box 55, Folder 1006)
      - Arkhitektura, drafts, [1990-1991] (Box 55, Folder 1007)
      - "Art is long," drafts, 1996?, 2000 (Box 55, Folder 1008)
      - "... as for your enemy, may I suggest the following," draft, 1996 (Box 55, Folder 1009)
      - At Carel Willink's Exhibition
        See:Na vystavke Karla Veilinka
      - At a lecture, drafts, proof and printed version, 1996, undated (Box 55, Folder 1010)
      - At the city dump in Nantucket, drafts, proof and printed version, 1995-2000 (Box 55, Folder 1011)
      - At the helmet and sword, draft and printed version, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 1012)
      - Autumn in Norenskaia
        See: Osen' v Norenskoi
      - August rain
        See:Dozhd' v avguste
      - Avgust, drafts, [1996] (Box 55, Folder 1013-1014)
      - Axiom
        See: "Mir sozdan byl iz smeshen'ia griazi, vody, ogonia"
      - Babochka
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 1015-1017)
          Series XI, Papers of Others -- Others -- Kees Verheul Papers
          Includes notes by Masha Vorobiov.